Conversion of Probabilities to the Sigma Scale
Welcome to this session on establishing baselines. We oftentimes get the question,
how do we convert from a probability to a Sigma?
Where do the PPM's come from, and all that?
Well, we can make these calculations in Excel.
For example, if I want to convert from a Sigma to a probability, I can put in the Sigma
and the probability I get back is a one tailed probability.
In other words, it means it's equivalent to a unilateral specification.
So, if I had a unilateral specification with a
short-term capability of Three Sigma,
That's the 66,807 ppm defective.
Notice, that I took into account the shift. I subtracted 1.5 from 3.
Sigma is always short-term, and defects per million opportunities.
DPMO here, is always long-term.
So, I account for that in my equation by simply subtracting 1.5.
And that's how I create that baseline if you will.
I can also convert defect to Sigma.
I go out measure the opportunities I got,
count the defects get my defects per million opportunities.
Come into handy-dandy Excel, make this calculation, and I can convert
probability back into to Sigma. DPMO back into Sigma.
Fairly simple and straight forward process.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.